Sanka Weerathunga

300 Dale Crescent Waterloo, ON, N2G 3Y3 (+1)778 6778 608

linkedin.com/Sanka-weerathunga

Solution <u>Solution</u> <u>Solution</u>

AWS Certified Data Analytics - Specialty & AWS Solution Architecture Associate with experience in Data engineering and analytics working with both structured and unstructured datasets in Data Lake environment, Data Warehousing and Cloud Computing.

Worked on analysis, design and implementation of enterprise data lake and data warehouse using AWS S3, Glue, IAM roles, Athena, PySpark and Azure SQL, Azure Databricks.

Worked on Spark-SQL with various data sources like JSON and Parquet in S3 and HDFS.

Skilled in developing Dimensional Data Modeling, Star Schema Modeling, Snow-Flake Modeling, FACT and Dimensions Tables.

Skills in both technical and functional applications of RDBMS, Data Mapping, Data management, Data Analysis, Data transportation and Data Staging.

Possesses strong knowledge of database management in writing complex **SQL queries**, analyzing execution plan and query optimization.

Worked on installing, configuring and automating **continuous integration and continuous deployment** tools. Experienced in creating and implementing interactive charts, graphs, and other user interface elements for reporting.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages : SQL, Python, PySpark, R, Scala, C#

Databases : Oracle Database, MS SQL Server, MySQL, KUDU, MongoDB, Couchbase

Data Science : Spark, Hadoop MapReduce

ETL : Airflow, Shell Script, PySpark, Databricks, AWS Glue

Cloud Platforms : Amazon Web Services, Azure, Databricks

Data Visualization : Microsoft Excel, Tableau, PowerBI, Python, R

Data Warehouse : AWS Redshift, Snowflake, Star Schema, Snowflake Schema

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Engineer

Jan 2019 - Dec 2022

Axiata Digital Labs

Sri Lanka

- Working in an agile team to develop real-time visualization (monitoring and operational) dashboards.
- Creating data pipelines using the Hadoop platform to extract data from real-time Kafka feeds using Kafka consumer programs into Kudu tables.
- Creating ETL processing Scripts using shell scripts.
- Prepossessing the data and combining hierarchy details, targets and more according to customer requests.
- Creating a daily monitoring process for the whole process to ensure every part of the data pipeline is running accurately
- Developing operational dashboards and analytical interactive dashboards using tableau for different levels of sales hierarchy.
- Produced the following dashboard additions to sales dashboards; Customer experience evaluation, Retailer performance evaluation, e-money fraud detection, etc.

Data Engineer Jul 2018 - Dec 2018

Dialog Axiata PLC Sri Lanka

• Developed analytical dashboards to evaluate customer experience in customer service centers using tableau.

Software Engineer Jun 2017 - Dec 2017

Asoft (Pvt) Ltd.

Sri Lanka

- Designed and implemented a web application, and an inventory management system using MVC (Model, View, Controller) architecture.
- Designed and implemented the backend modules.
- Designed the database schema.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

An advanced back-testing tool for forex Traders

- Developed enhanced back-testing tool that includes four main features: short-term price trend predictions and hybrid back-testing to evaluate forex trading strategies, trading strategy optimization and anomalous time periods detection.
- Developed a model to predict short-term trends in forex market prices using price data of EURUSD currency pair by combining a Recurrent Neural Network with an ARIMA (time series forecasting) model.

EDUCATION

Ontario College Graduate Certificate (Post-Graduate)

Sep 2023 - Present

ON, Canada

Conestoga College

• Field of study: Big Data Solution Architecture

• Current GPA: 3.86

Bachelor of Science (Honors) in Information Technology

Mar 2014 - Aug 2018

University of Moratuwa

Sri Lanka

• Publications: Weerathunga HPSD, Silva AT. DRNN-ARIMA Approach to Short-term Trend Forecasting in Forex Market.18th International Conference on Advances in ICT for Emerging Regions (ICTer)Sep. 2018 (pp. 287-293).

CERTIFICATES

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate Amazon Web Services Training and Certification	May 2023
AWS Certified Data Analytics – Specialty Amazon Web Services Training and Certification	Aug 2023
Big Data Modelling and Management Systems Coursera	Nov 2019
Google Cloud Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure	Jun 2019
Coursera	
Distributed Computing with Spark SQL	Feb 2023

Coursera